Richard S. Kearse

Arlington, VA 22204 | 571-431-9682 | richard.kearse@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-kearse

Front End SharePoint Analyst

Top Secret (SSBI) SharePoint professional with over 9 years of expertise in IT and a passion for Front-End Web Design. I am a team-oriented creative dedicated to designing, developing, and implementing custom solutions on the Microsoft SharePoint platform.

Expertise

- SharePoint 2010/2013
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Site Development
- Site Troubleshooting
- Coding & Programming
- UI & UX Design
- Agile SCRUM
- Customer Interaction
- On-Site Client Support

Clearances

Top Secret SSBI (2012) | Public Trust/Confidential (2011)

Professional Experience

Applied Information Sciences - DoD, Arlington, VA Project Server Administrator (12/2016 - Present)

- Built, maintained, and supported custom solutions on the Microsoft Project Server and SharePoint 2013 framework using OOTB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and AJAX.
- Provide program training, documentation, and deskside assistance to help the customer use the system effectively and efficiently.
- Collaborate with the Project Server SME and server team to enhance the back-end.

Applied Information Sciences - DoD/SharePoint Center of Excellence. Arlington, VA SharePoint Analyst (9/2016 - 12/2016)

- Lead Analyst for the migration of over 2,000 SharePoint 2010 sites to 2013.
- Developed custom SharePoint sites using OOTB, HTML and CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Designed and implemented SharePoint workflows and forms using SharePoint Designer and InfoPath.

Applied Information Sciences - FBI SharePoint Consultant (5/2016 - 9/2016)

- Provided UI layout and custom designs for multiple SharePoint 2013 sites, using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery, which resulted in a unique and customized SharePoint presence for each department.
- Assisted in maintaining, supporting, and developing custom AJAX solutions utilizing SharePoint 2013's REST service.

Applied Information Sciences - DoD/SharePoint Center of Excellence, Arlington, VA SharePoint Analyst (3/2013 - 4/2016)

- Developed consistent branding and navigation using UI & workflows with master pages,
 CSS, JS, SharePoint Designer, and other features, thus enhancing the user experience.
- Integrated JS components into sites, libraries and lists by adding accordions, charts, icons, menus and forms for a customized look and feel.
- Collaborated with end users and stakeholders to gather requirements, identify process challenges, and design new SharePoint 2010 and 2013 solutions to reduce costs and streamline business processes.
- Resolved Remedy tickets through site creation, utilization, and troubleshooting errors to support OSD employees in their day-to-day business processes.

Applied Information Sciences - FBI, Washington, D.C. SharePoint Support Analyst (10/2012 - 3/2014)

- Assisted the SharePoint Delta team by collaborating, troubleshooting and resolving user inquiries to help maximize the customers use of the system.
- Built and released Delta updates and new versions using customer feedback and product backlog, enhancing the application.
- Coordinated training sessions and created documentation to support new and existing system features.

Vertical Integrations/Seneca - DoD/ATL, Pentagon Tier 2 Help Desk Technician (1/2012 - 10/2012)

- Provided Tier 2 deskside and phone support. Captured and responded to a wide variety of desktop/laptop hardware and software issues within a Microsoft Windows environment.
- Handled incoming calls, system alerts, and assist users both in person and over the phone meeting Service Level Agreement (SLA) deadlines.

Indigo IT - FHFA, Washington, D.C. IT Support Specialist (10/2010 - 1/2012)

• Provided Tier 1-3 technical and end-user mobile, remote, and deskside support for the Federal Government's hardware and software applications.

United Services Organization - Arlington, VA Help Desk Support Technician (4/2009 – 8/2010)

• Troubleshooted and resolved hardware, software, and network issues locally and remotely, maximizing organizational productivity and network stability.

Education

THE GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY • Web Development | Graduation est. Oct. 2018 EAST CAROLINA UNIVERSITY • B.S. in Communications | Business Minor

Certifications

- Security+, CompTIA, 2015
- MOS 2013, Microsoft, 2014
- MOS 2010, Microsoft, 2013

- Network +, CompTIA, 2010
- A+, CompTIA, 2009

Additional Skills

Boloney Time Machine | www.boloneytimemachine.com Web Designer, Developer, Creator, and Illustrator (2015-Present)

Create, illustrate, design and maintain the comic strips art and website using Adobe Suite, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, and Visual Studio Code.

HTML5; CSS3; JavaScript; jQuery; Bootstrap; Adobe Creative Cloud;

AJAX; Windows; Visual Studio Code